（シカマル）いの　チョウジ
とっとと終わらせて帰るぜ。
Ino, Choji...
Let's get this over with
and go home.
（いの）わかってるって！
ねっ　チョウジ。　ん？
We know. Right, Choji?
Huh?
チョウジ！？
Choji?!
- That idiot!
- Cripes...
あいつ～！
ったく　いの　フォーメーション…。
[無線]わかってるわよ！！
- Ino, go with formation-
- I know!
影首縛りの術！
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
《頼んだぞ　いの。
I'm counting on you, Ino.
今のチャクラじゃ
これが精一杯だ》
With the chakra I have now,
this is my limit.
いくわよ！　心転身の術！
Here I go!
Mind Transfer Jutsu!
どうやら　成功みてえだな。
Looks like it worked.
（チョウジ）ふぅ…　やっぱりねぇ。
I figured as much.
超倍化の術！
Super Expansion Jutsu!
ちょっと　チョウジ！
さぼってんじゃないわよ！！
Hey Choji!
How could you slack off?!
This hunt was your idea
in the first place!
だいたい　この狩りは
あんたの提案でしょ！！
Food is the foundation of survival.
食事は　生活の基本だよ。
The village is in the midst of a crisis,
so we have to make sure we eat.
里が大変なときだからこそ
しっかり食べて…。
Well, you're the only one
taking a break here!
なら　１人だけ
休んでんじゃないわよ！
What if they got away?
逃げられたら
どうするつもりだったのよ！
え？　だって　シカマルなら
きっとこうすると思ってたから。
Huh?
Well, I knew Shikamaru
could do this.
はぁ…。
Come to think of it...
《そういや　こいつも
俺の指示の前に…》
She also knew what to do
before I said anything.
ano suiheisen ga touzakatte iku
Far beyond the horizon it continues
ao sugita sora ni wa ashita sura egake nakute
A sky so blue, you can't draw tomorrow
iki mo dekinai kurai yodonda hito no mure
It's stifling with crowds of people down here
boku wa itsukara koko ni moguri kondan da?
Just when did I dive into this?
kanashimi nante hakidashite mae dake mi tereba iin dakke?
Spit out sadness and keep looking ahead, right?
sore ja totemo matomo de irarenai
You can't stay true to yourself like that
subete o boku ga teki ni mawashite mo
Even if I turn against everything,
hikari o kasuka ni kanji terun da
I still feel glimmers of light
soko made yuke sou nara
If I could only reach it...
iki o shitakute koko wa kurushikute
I want to breathe, I'm suffocating here
yami o miageru dake no boku ja
Only looking up into the dark means,
ukabu houhou mo nai daibaa
I'm a diver who can't surface
iki o shite mite
Take a deep breath
tada no shiawase ni kizuitara mou nidoto oborenai yo
Discover joy, plain and simple and you'll never drown
- Leaf's History -
Team 10's Teamwork
あいつら　鬼じゃ…。
They're demons.
They appear every year
during the harvest.
毎年　収穫の季節になると
現れおって。
じゃから　わしらも→
So this year, we were prepared
to die fighting them off.
今年は　死ぬ気で
戦うつもりだったのじゃ。
しかし　ずる賢いバジのやつ
わしの計画を知ってか知らずか→
But that sly Baji...
I don't know if he knew my plan or not,
but he kidnapped my granddaughter.
孫娘をかどわかしおって…。
（カカシ）その　バジというのが…。
This Baji is...
（トウフウ）この村の収穫を狙う
バジ盗賊団の頭領です。
He's the boss of the bandits
who steal our crops.
Please... Please... save our village and
my granddaughter from those bandits!
どうか　どうか…
何とぞ　盗賊から村を…。
孫娘を救ってくだされ。
（アスマ）その方は？
And you are?
元盗賊の　トウフウじゃ。
This is Tofu, a former member
of the bandits.
（カカシ）元盗賊？
（トウフウ）疑われてもしかたない。
An ex-bandit?
I don't blame you
for mistrusting me.
しかし　あいつらのやり方に
俺は　ついていけなくなったんだ。
But I couldn't go along with
their ways anymore.
孫娘がさらわれたことを
教えてくれたのも　トウフウなのじゃ。
Tofu here told me of
my granddaughter's abduction.
それに　元盗賊なればこその
案内もありましょうぞ。
As an ex-bandit,
he can be an invaluable guide.
That's true.
それは　まぁ　そうですね。
Please allow me to help.
よろしくお願いします。
それじゃ　出発の準備だ。
Well then,
let's get ready to move.
（ナルト）オッス！
（シカマルたち）はい！
- Yes, sir.
- Right!
シカマル　ちょっといいか？
Shikamaru, got a minute?
ん？
The hideout is
a natural fortification
（トウフウ）盗賊のアジトは
天然の要塞の中。
deep inside a cavern that
fans out like an ant's nest.
アリの巣状に広がる
洞窟の奥にあって→
There is only one route to it.
たどり着くには　ルートは１つ。
しかし　そのルートには
堅牢な砦が３つもあり→
But along this route are three forts
that each serve as a checking station.
関所の役割をしています。
But the trickiest part is Baji's intelligence.
It's why he's so feared.
もっとも
いちばんやっかいなのは→
知将バジと恐れられた
頭領の頭脳でしょうか。
（カカシ）今回の任務は
第一が人質救出。
The main purpose of this mission
is to rescue the hostage.
ついで　盗賊団との戦闘だ。
And that will involve
a confrontation with the bandits.
シカマル　どう思う？
Shikamaru, what do you think?
そうっすねぇ…。
Well...
彼は下忍とはいえ
なかなかの策士でしてね。
He may still be a genin,
but he's a skilled tactician.
ルートが１つといっても→
There may only be one route,
but we're not moving a large force.
大軍を動かすわけじゃ
ないっすからね…。
俺たちだけなら
砦を通らずに行くことも→
Since it's just us,
maybe we can bypass the forts.
できるかもしれないっすね。
Having said that,
とはいえ　やつらも
そんなことは警戒済みだから…。
I'm sure they've set up their defenses
and laid considerable traps.
かなりの罠を仕掛けてるはず。
それでも　人質救出後に
戦闘を避けて戻るには→
But it's our best chance to get out
without fighting the enemy
それが最善。
after we make the rescue.
最低限の安全ルートは
確認したいとこっすね。
At the very least, we need to confirm
that there's a safe passage.
（アスマ）なるほど。
I see.
まずは強行偵察で
小部隊が潜入できるルート探しか…。
So the first thing to do is to find
a way for a small team to infiltrate.
All right! Let's go!
よっしゃ！　早速　行くってばよ！
We genin are staying behind.
俺たちゃ　留守番だ。
え～！？
What?!
さっきも言ったけどよ→
Like I just said, the enemy knows
every detour already.
迂回ルートなんてのは
敵も想定済み。
それを悟られずに
行き来できるのは…。
The only ones who are capable
of going undetected
カカシ先生と　アスマのツーマンセルだけだ。
are Kakashi Sensei and Asuma.
この任務は
２人にやってもらうのが　ベスト…。
It's best to let them handle this.
だと思うんすけどね。
That's my opinion.
さすがだな。
それしかないだろう　カカシ。
He's right.
There's no other way, Kakashi.
Yes.
うむ。
まぁ　そう　むくれるな　ナルト。
Don't be so upset, Naruto.
あとは頼んだぞ　シカマル。
しゃあないっすね。
Take care of things here, Shikamaru.
I guess I'll have to.
まっ　そういうわけだから→
As you heard,
please wait here for a while.
しばらく　ここで
待ってもらいますよ。
あれ？
そういえば　トウフウさんは？
Huh?
Hey, where's Tofu?
便所だとよ。
Nature called.
What's the big idea?!
（トウフウ）何しやがる！？
What was that shout?!
なんだ！？　今の声。
（サスケ）おい　あれを見ろ。
Hey, look over there.
トウフウさんじゃねえのか！？
Tofu!
（サクラ）捕まった！？
どういうこと？
He's been captured?!
But how?
Jeez...
まったく…。
どうすんだってばよ！？
What'll we do?!
Hey! Don't just sit there!
おい！
なに　のんきに座って…。
相手は　数十人の盗賊集団…。
The enemy is a gang of bandits
with scores of men.
人質に　砦が３つ…
その先に本丸だ。
They have a hostage
and three forts.
And beyond that,
the inner fortress.
めんどくせえが
俺たちだけでやってみっか。
It'll be a pain,
but I guess we'll do it ourselves.
Boss Baji!
バジのお頭！　例の脱走者です。
I brought the deserter!
Good. You can go now.
（バジ）ご苦労　下がっていいぞ。
へい。
Yes sir!
ふぅ～…　お～　痛っ…。
Oww...
よく来たな。
Welcome.
へっ…　ったくよぉ…。
Cripes...
Train your guys properly!
手下を　ちゃんと　しつけとけよ。
おらぁ　貴重な情報屋だぜ。
Remember,
I'm a valuable informant.
すまんな。
たとえ　合言葉を知っていても→
Sorry.
They're trained to be suspicious
even if the password is correct.
疑えと教育してるもんでな。
まっ　慎重なあんたらしいな。
Well, you always take precautions.
で　情報は手に入ったのか？
So you brought me information?
へへっ…
村はやはり　忍を雇った。
The village hired ninja, after all.
うむ…　で　戦力は？
And? How strong are they?
上忍２人と　下忍が６人。
Two jonin and six genin.
Two small teams made up
mostly of genin?
下忍主体の２小隊か…。
上忍さえのぞけば
大した戦力とはいえんな。
Once we get rid of the jonin,
they won't be a problem at all.
Yeah. And the two jonin aren't
with them right now.
あぁ　その上忍２人は
今　隊を離れてるぜ。
ほう…　なぜだ？
Really. Why's that?
They're looking for a way to get here
without passing through the forts.
（トウフウ）砦を通らずに
ここへ来るルートを探している。
（バジ）フッ…　俺でも
一応は　そうするかな。
That's what I'd do too.
まっ　そこに罠があることを
想定していなければ→
But if they don't anticipate traps
along the way, it'll be a mission of death.
死の任務ということになるがな。
One of them saw that far ahead.
そこまで考えているやつがいた。
He's a genin named Shikamaru.
He had that figured out already.
シカマルという下忍なんだが→
迂回ルートの罠は読んでいたぜ。
砦を見て　迂回ルートを探し→
So a two-man cell
made up of jonin
罠を警戒して
上忍だけのツーマンセルを送り込む…。
bypasses our forts and
are on the alert for traps.
その程度の策じゃ→
As if a simple strategy like
that will work against me.
到底　このバジ様の敵ではない。
Boss!
お頭！
ん？
B-Boss! It's a ninja!
お　お頭　忍です！
三重砦を突破して→
They managed to get through
our three forts!
忍が現れやした！
な　何だと！？
W-What?!
砦からの連絡は　どうなってる！？
Why was there no word
from the forts?!
それが急に現れたんで
何が何やら…。
They just suddenly appeared.
I don't know what's going on.
万が一に備えての三重砦だぞ。
Those three forts are there to
prevent just this sort of thing!
そんなバカな話があるか！？
It's impossible!
貴様　まさか二重スパイじゃ
ないだろうな！？
You! Are you a double agent?!
砦の連中と
グルになって　やつらを…。
Don't tell me you're in cahoots with
the men at the forts and let these ninja...
そんなことしてねえ！
本当だよ　信じてくれ！
N-No way!
I'm serious.
You've got to believe me!
口じゃあ　何とでも言える。
そうだ！
Talk is cheap.
I-I know!
やつらは
俺が捕まったと思い込んでる。
Look, they think I've been captured!
忍と俺を人質交換すれば
やつらの足止めにもなるし→
If you use me for
a hostage exchange,
I'll be able to stall them and
send you information!
また　やつらの情報を
入手することもできる！
ふん…。
こいつを　ここに置いておいても
何の足しにもならないが→
Keeping you here
doesn't do any good.
人質交換に使えるなら
やつらの頭を潰すことができるか。
But if I use you for a hostage exchange,
I'll be able to crush their leader.
手札は
多いに越したことはないからな。
The more cards to play, the better.
よっしゃ！
全員ぶっとばしてやるぜ！
All right!
Let's pulverize them all!
焦るな　ナルト。
えぇ！？
- Slow down, Naruto.
- Huh?
人質がいることを忘れたのか。
Don't forget that there's a hostage.
アジトを落とすのは
そう難しくねえだろうが→
Bringing down their hide-out
might not be that difficult,
まずは村長の孫娘が
どこにいるのかを→
but we've got to find
the village headman's granddaughter first.
突き止めねえとな。
おう…。
でも　どうやって？
O-Oh right.
But how?
やつらの次の手を利用する。
We'll take advantage
of their next move.
次の手って？
Next move?
やつらの次の手は
人質交換ってとこだろう。
Which is a hostage exchange.
引きこもりの連中が
考えそうなことだが。
That's plausible if
they don't want a confrontation.
人質交換ってことは→
A hostage exchange?
僕たちの誰かが
人質になるってこと？
You mean one of us has
to become a hostage?
シカマル！　出てこい　話がある。
Shikamaru!
Come on out.
I want to talk to you!
こいつを助けたければ→
If you want to save him,
how about you take his place?
お前とこいつで
人質交換といこうじゃないか。
ふんっ　やっぱそうきたか。
Just as I expected.
返事をしろ！　シカマル！
What's your answer, Shikamaru?!
あぁ！　いいぜ！
Okay. Fine!
《俺の問いに答えたな》
He answered my question.
ここまでは俺の読みどおりだ。
So far, it's going as I expected.
《なんだ？　声が出ねえ》
What the-? My voice is gone?!
ハハハ　秘伝術　口縫いの術。
My Hidden Jutsu: Muting Jutsu.
しゃべれなければ　どんな作戦も
伝えることはできまい。
If you can't speak, you can't convey
any strategy you come up with.
《信じるしかねえか》
I just have to have faith.
何　考えてるのよ。
あいつ…。
What is he thinking?
That idiot.
おい　勝手に行くなよ！
Hey! Don't go off
on your own.
いや　何の考えもなしに
行動するようなシカマルじゃない。
Listen...
Shikamaru would never
take action without a plan.
そうよ。
He's right.
この人質交換を利用すると
シカマルは言ったのよ。
Shikamaru said to take advantage
of this hostage exchange.
《でも　それはいったい…》
But what did he mean by that?
ご迷惑をおかけしました。
I'm sorry for the trouble I caused.
演技をしなくていいってばよ。
え？
You don't have to pretend.
Huh?
お前がスパイだってのは…。
とっくに気づいてたんだからね。
We were aware that you were a spy.
A long time ago.
ヘヘヘ…。
それならば　なぜ…。
If... If that's the case, why?
お兄ちゃん
助けに来てくれたの？
Did you come to save me?
どうやって砦を抜けてきた？
おっと　まだ俺の術中だったな。
How did you bypass the forts?
Oh right,
you're still under my jutsu.
解！
Release!
もう大丈夫だからな。
It's going to be all right now.
どうやって
砦を抜けたのか聞いている。
I asked how you bypassed the forts!
簡単なことさ。
That was easy.
俺たちは　トウフウが怪しいと
初めから思っていた。
We were suspicious
of Tofu all along.
そこでだ。
So we secretly placed
a mini-wireless on him.
小型の無線機をトウフウに仕込んだ。
（バジ）何！？
What?
案の定　やつは
砦の合言葉をしゃべってくれた。
And as expected,
he said the password.
((峠のユリは　夜に輝く))
The lilies on the mountain pass
shine at night.
だが俺は　合言葉なんぞ
そもそも信用しちゃいない。
But I've never trusted passwords.
砦の連中にも　それは
言い聞かせてあったはずだ。
And those guys at the forts
had strict orders.
あいつら　あんたほどは
疑い深くはないようだ。
But it seems they're not
as suspicious as you are.
合言葉を知ってるスパイが→
We told them,
俺たちの前に
ここを通過したはずだ。
"A spy who knows the password
should have come through before us."
俺たちは　そいつを追っている。
こう言ったら→
"We're pursuing him."
信用して通してくれたぜ。
（バジ）な…　何だと！？
And they let us pass.
W-What?
子供だましには
ちげぇねえが→
It was a childish prank,
but it worked nicely.
意外と効果的だったなぁ。
フッ…　お前が
ただのガキじゃないってことは→
You're no child,
I'll grant you that.
認めてやろう。
だがな　小ざかしい策士も
今や囚われの身。
Still, even if you're a smart little tactician,
you're just a prisoner right now.
残りの下忍なんぞ　俺の策で
軽くひねり潰してやるさ。
And I have my own strategy
to wipe out your genin pals.
怖がることはないぜ。
Don't be afraid.
すぐに仲間が
助けにきてくれるからな。
My friends will be here
soon to save us.
強がりはよせ。
忍の術が　いかに強くとも→
Don't try to be brave.
Ninjutsu may be powerful,
人質を傷つけずに
砦を破壊することは不可能。
but there's no way to destroy this place
without harming the hostage.
そのための人質。
That's the reason for
having a hostage.
お前　トウフウを
こちらのスパイと知りつつ→
Wait!
If you knew Tofu was my spy, why did you
agree to the hostage exchange?!
なぜ　人質交換に応じた！？
フッ…　さあてね。
Who knows?
火遁　豪火球の術！
Fire Style! Fire Ball Jutsu!
城攻め？
軍師を失った下忍どもが→
An assault?
The loss of their leader throws
the genin into a panic
ヤケになって
人質ごと城を潰す。
and they attack the castle,
regardless of the hostages.
そう見せかける陽動作戦か？
Is that the diversionary tactic?
が　人質がいる限り
全力での攻撃は無理。
But as long as there are hostages involved,
a full-on attack is impossible.
そして　この場所を
外の下忍どもが知る術はない。
And the other genin have
no jutsu to locate this spot.
切り札がこちらにある限り→
I hold the trump card.
There's no way you can win.
いくらあがこうが
お前らに勝機はない。
うろたえるな！
こんなときのために→
Calm down!
The boss planned for times like this!
お頭が立てた
作戦があんだろ！
そうだ！　ここは天然の要塞。
大群は攻めこめない！
Right! This place is
a natural fortification!
A large force cannot penetrate us!
どうしたんだ？
What is it?
お頭！
何だ？
Boss!
What is it?
新手です！
新手の忍が現れやした！
New ones!
More ninja just appeared!
いちいち
うろたえるな。
Quit panicking each time!
その程度のこと
授けた策で何とでもなるだろうが。
Didn't I give you contingent plans
to handle something like that?
し　しかし…。
B-But...
千人なろうかという大群が。
It's an army of a thousand.
せ　千人だと！？
A thousand?!
ヘヘヘ…　シカマルもいねえし→
Shikamaru's not here.
もう　誰も俺を
止められねえってばよ！
So no one can stop me now!
シカマルと人質がいるのは
西の塔。
Shikamaru and the hostage
are in the west tower.
そこを崩さないように
すればいいんだね。
So we make sure not to
destroy that one, right?
間違いないわ　チョウジ。
You got it, Choji!
よし　倍化の術！
Okay!
Expansion Jutsu!
肉弾戦車！！
Human Boulder!
いっけ～　チョウジ！！
Go Choji!
お兄ちゃん
何だか楽しそうね。
You seem to be enjoying this.
ん？　そんなふうに見えるかい？
Huh? Do I?
お兄ちゃんは　怖くないの？
あぁ。
Aren't you scared?
Nope.
どうして？
Why?
仲間を信じてるからな。
Because I have faith in my friends.
調子にのるなよ　小僧。
切り札は　こっちにあるんだ。
Don't get cocky, kid!
I hold the trump card!
人質を盾に
逃げたっていいんだからな。
I can get away with the hostage
as my shield!
村長の孫娘さえいりゃあ
取り引きは　どうとでもなる。
As long as I have
the headman's granddaughter,
I can negotiate my way out.
ここへ　下忍のガキどもが来る前に
とんずらすりゃあ→
If I escape before the genin brats get here,
your plans won't mean a thing.
お前らの策なんざ
無に等しい。
仲間を放って逃げるのか？
You would abandon your men?
仲間だと？　くだらねえ。
My men? What a laugh!
俺さえ無事なら　こんな盗賊団→
As long as I get out alive,
I can form a new gang anytime.
いくつだって作ることが
できるんだ。
んっ！？
（２人）シカマル！
- Shikamaru!
シカマル。
大丈夫！？
- Shikamaru!
- Are you all right?
あぁ…　ギリギリだったがな…。
Yeah, but just barely.
それは　こっちのセリフよ！
心配かけて！
That's our line!
You gave us such a scare!
ど…　どうして
この場所が　わかった！？
H-How did you find this place?
木ノ葉には　山中一族って
秘伝忍術を使う一族がいる。
The Yamanaka clan
of the Hidden Leaf
use a Hidden Jutsu called
Mind Transfer Jutsu.
心転身の術。
あんたなら
聞いたことくらい　あるだろ？
I'm sure you've at least heard of it.
心転身の術。
Mind Transfer Jutsu?!
（シカマル）あの時…。
Back there...
((心転身の術！))
Mind Transfer Jutsu!
（シカマル）いのは　心転身の術を使い→
Through her Mind Transfer Jutsu,
Ino used my eyes to find this place.
俺の目を通して
この場所を知り…。
((解！
Release!
(みんな！　人質とシカマルの居場所が
わかったわ))
Everyone, I know where Shikamaru
and the hostage are being held!
てなわけだ。
So now you know.
冗談じゃないわよ！
Don't be ridiculous!
私が　シカマルの作戦に
気づかなかったら→
What would you have done if
I hadn't figured out your plan?!
どうするつもりだったのよ！
（チョウジ）確かに　ハラハラしたね。
It was touch-and-go there for a while.
ふざけるな！
それじゃあ　何か？
That's crazy!
Don't tell me you
knew from the start
俺が　お前とトウフウを
人質交換すると→
that I would call for a hostage exchange
with you for Tofu?!
はじめから
わかっていたということか！？
カードを失ったプレイヤーは
手札を補充したがるだろ？
When a player loses a card,
he wants to replace it, right?
カ…　カード…。
A card?
（シカマル）今回のことで言えば
お前が準備したカードは→
Well, in your case the card
was your three forts.
三重の砦だ。
それを失ったとき→
Once you lost them, you needed to
replace them as quickly as possible.
次なる策のために
カードを　準備したくなる。
手っ取り早く
手に入れる方法は　１つ。
それが　人質交換だと！？
Through a hostage exchange.
あんたみたいに
慎重で　情報を重視する策略家は→
A tactician like you analyzes
every bit of data,
同時に　相手の作戦を
いちばん警戒するからな。
and at the same time, places top priority
on his enemy's strategy.
俺を狙ってくるのは
容易に　想像がついた。
I knew right off the bat
that you'd target me.
そういうわけさ。
That's all.
フッ。
見事　見事。　完敗だよ。
Amazing. Simply amazing.
I lose.
I've got to hand it to you.
すごいよ　君は。
俺は　すごくなんかねえ。
I'm not amazing.
ほんとに　すげえのは
俺の信じる仲間たちのほうだぜ。
What's amazing are my friends
who believe in me.
ほざけ！
Shut up!
（チョウジ）起爆札！？
A Paper Bomb!
少しでも動いてみろ。
貴様ら全員　道連れにしてやる！
Just try and make a move!
I'll blow you all up!
いいか？　少しでも…　ううっ！？
Did you hear?
If you make a move...
影真似の術…　成功。
My Shadow Possession Jutsu worked.
（カカシ）ありゃ～
今年のルーキーたちは　優秀だね。
My my... This year's rookies
are quite talented.
（アスマ）聞いたぞ　シカマル。
作戦も伝えずに行動するとは→
We heard it all, Shikamaru.
That was quite a risk you took taking action
without relaying your strategy to the others.
ずいぶんと　大きなギャンブルに
出たじゃないか。
まっ　結果オーライってことで
シカマル君は　よくやってくれたよ。
Well, it ended successfully.
So job well done, Shikamaru.
ギャンブルなんて　してないっす。
それに…→
It wasn't a gamble.
Besides I just watched my friends work
and had faith in them. That's all.
俺は　仲間を信じて見てただけ。
何もしちゃいねえっすよ。
こいつらなら　言葉はなくても→
Even without words,
I knew these guys would understand.
伝わってるって
思ってましたからね。
《思えば　俺たち十班は→
When I think about it, Team 10 always
had each other's backs during battle.
ずっと　信頼しあって
戦ってきたんだな…。
いや　それは　俺たちだけじゃねえ。
No, it wasn't just Team 10.
Naruto, Lee, Kiba, all of us.
ナルトたちだって
リーやキバたちも　そうだ。
そして　仲間を信じる想いは
班なんて枠を越えて→
Our faith in our friends has spread past
our teams, and into the entire village.
里全体へと　広がってんだな…。
そう思うだろ？　アスマ…》
Right, Asuma?
ったく　しゃあねえな。
Oh well. Shall we go back
and have some barbeque?
帰って　焼肉にするか。
やった～！
Yes!
あっ　ちょ…　待ってよ。
Hey, wait up!
チョウジは　罰として
獲物を　里まで運ぶのよ。
As punishment, you get to carry
the catch back to the village, Choji.
そんな～　手伝ってよ～。
Oh come on.
Help me out here.
フッ。
《策士だなんだと
言われちゃいるが→
People may call me a tactician,
こいつらにゃ　俺の手の内なんか
バレバレなんだよな…》
but these guys know everything
there is about me.
mayonaka no utaga sakenda
The poetry of midnight cries out,
boku hontou wa ano hi kara zutto
"Ever since that day, I actually..."
akaku sukitooru yuugure no ato
After the twilight in hues of red,
hoshi tachi wa sora ni tsuwari sorezore no oto kanadeteitta
Stars sit on the sky, Each making their own sound
sunao ni nare to iware nakutemo
You don't need to tell me to be true to myself
namida wa mo boku no omoi tsurete
My tears have already taken my feelings
ashi moto de chiisana umi ni natta
and formed a small ocean at my feet
sora wa ugokanai higa nobori oriru dake
The sky is still. Only the sun rises and sets
jimen wa ugokanai kimi ga arukuka arukanaika dake da
The ground is still. It's up to you to take a step or not
mayonaka no uta ga sakenda
The poetry of midnight cries out,
boku hontou wa hitori ga kirai da
"I actually hate being alone. I hate it"
dai kirai da taisetsu wo shitte shimatta ano hi kara zutto
Since that day I learned what was important
aa shiawase nante chiisana spoon de tsukueru kurai de
A small spoonful of happiness is more than enough
jyuubun nanda wakeaeru hito ga iruka inaika dake da
It's just whether you have someone to share it with or not
Next Episode
（くもじい）もしもし
そこの　あなた。
I have a mission for Team 7!
たまには　空から
日本を眺めてみるというのは→
Then again, it appears things are not
going well between Naruto and Sasuke.
どうじゃろう？
今回　わしらが飛ぶのは
常磐線じゃ。
I'm embarrassed to say it,
but yes.
It cannot be helped.
（くもみ）常磐線。
You and Sasuke will handle
this mission.
この沿線には　見たことのない→
What shall I do with
Naruto and Sakura?
不思議なものが
いっぱい　あるぞ。
Don't worry. I just happen to have
the perfect assignment for them.
うわっ　なんか　いますね。
他にも
千葉などに　こんな町とか。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Drive Towards Darkness"
Drive Towards Darkness
あっ　これって。
This is also for the mission!
では　そろそろ出発じゃ。